Edwin Augustus Porcher Collection
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
- Drawings, Series I
  - Drawings from the HMS Hibernia
    - 61. Malta. The cemetery at the Naval Hospital. June 19, 1857., 1857 June 19; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 25.25 x 36 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      The largest in the British empire, the Royal Naval hospital was situated near the walled city of Valetta, on the north side of the island (Gatewood). Legible on one of the tombstones are the names Dr. W. Martin and his wife, Eliza Martin.
      B1977.14.222154
      Cemeteries; Watercolors; Royal Naval Hospital (Malta)
    - 62. Malta. H.M.S. Hibernia in the Dockyard Creek. March 13, 1857., 1857 March 13; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 26 x 36 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      B1977.14.22152
      The Hibernia, launched at Portsmouth in 1804, was a specially fitted 120 gun 'receiving and guard ship'. In this view, the ship is docked next to Fort St. Angelo (Castrum Maris), at the tip of the Vittoriosa Promontory, Grand Harbor of Malta. The British admiralty established its first dry dock in 1848, and the Grand Harbor grew as a key base for the Royal Navy. Dockyard Creek was also an important source of employment for the island's growing number of inhabitants (Atauz 181-2).
      Malta; Grand Harbour (Malta); Watercolors; Hibernia (Ship: 1804-1902)
    - 63. Malta. Part of Valetta, and Floriana, with H.M.S. Harpy in the Dockyard Creek. March 22, 1858, 1858 March 22; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 26 x 36 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      Porcher was appointed the command of the small paddle wheel HMS Harpy on May 1, 1858 replacing the ailing Lieutenant Bruce, to transport the archaeologist Nathan Davis to Tunisia. Porcher and crew were essential to Nathan Davis's archaeological mission, not only assisting with excavation work but transporting removed sculptures and pavement from the dig sites.
      B1977.14.22158
      Malta; Watercolors; Valletta (Malta); Furjana (Malta); Harpy (Ship: 1845-1909)
    - 64. Malta. Looking up the Dockyard Creek. May 15, 1857., 1857 May 15; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 26 x 36 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      B1977.14.22153
      Watercolors; Malta; Valletta (Malta)
    - 65. Malta. The Admiral Superindent's [sic] house, and the Victualling Yard. July 20. 1859., 1859 July 20; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 25.25 x 14.5 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      B1977.14.22181
      Malta; Watercolors
    - 70. Malta. Phoenician ruins of Crendi, or Hagiar Chem, and the Island of Fifla. Sept. 28, 1858., 1858 September 28; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 25.25 x 35.5 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      Charles Newton, Keeper of Antiquities at the British Museum, described Crendi as a complex of ruins of two temples, supposedly Phoenician, one on the summit of a hill and the other near the sea. The large blocks of stone, "like Stonehenge" were believed to form a link between prehistoric cultures and early Greek art. ( Gentleman's Magazine, July, 1852, 80).
      B1977.14.22175
      Antiquities; Qrendi (Malta); Malta -- Antiquities; Malta; Excavations (Archaeology); Watercolors
    - 71. Malta. The ruins of Crendi. Sept. 16. 1858., 1858 September 16; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 25.25 x 35.5 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      Sketches of the ruins of Crendi exhibited by "Mr. Colnaghi" may have popularized the site as an artistic subject. (see Charles Newton, Gentleman's Magazine, July, 1852, 80).
      B1977.14.22174
      Antiquities; Malta; Qrendi (Malta); Excavations (Archaeology); Malta -- Antiquities; Watercolors
    - 73. Malta. Fomm El Rih on the south side of the island. April 20. 1860., 1860 April 20; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 25.25 x 35.5 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      B1977.14.22189
      Watercolors; Malta; Fomm ir-Riħ (Malta)
    - 76. Malta. Statue of St. Paul on the Island of Salmone. June 4, 1859., 1859 June 4; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 17.75 x 25.25 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      Malta's historical association with St. Paul is linked to the biblical account of his shipwreck, said to have occurred off the island's coast at a site today known as St. Paul's Bay. Pictured here by Porcher, a colossal statue of St. Paul was erected in the nineteenth century on Salmone (referred to as "Selmoon Island").
      B1977.14.22180
      Watercolors; Saint Paul's Island (Malta); Statues; Paul, the Apostle, Saint
    - 77. Malta. The Protestant college, near St. Julian's Bay. April 25, 1860., 1860 April 25; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 17.75 x 25.25 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      B1977.14.22190
      Watercolors; Malta Protestant College
    - 78. Malta. Part of Wignacourt's aqueduct leading across the St. Gieuseppe Road. March 20, 1860., 1860 March 20; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 18 x 25.25 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      Grand Master Alof de Wignacourt commissioned the aqueduct bearing his name, which appears in Porcher's drawing. Constructed in 1615 by the architect Bontadino de Bontadini, it supplied fresh water to the city of Valletta from the plateau at the island's interior (Phillips n.p.).
      B1977.14.22186
      Watercolors; Wignacourt Aqueduct (Malta); Aqueducts
    - 79. Malta. The new church at Musta. March 15, 1860., 1860 March 15; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 17.75 x 25.25 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      B1977.14.22185
      Watercolors; Church Buildings; Mosta Rotunda (Church: Mosta, Malta)
    - 80. Malta. A triumphal arch, built by the last Grand Master Hompesch, March 23, 1858., 1858 March 23; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 18 x 23.5 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      B1997.14.22159
      Triumphal arches; Watercolors; Hompesch Gate (Zabbar, Malta); Hompesch, Ferdinand, Freiherr von, 1744-1805
    - 81. Malta. Tower in a garden belonging to the Marquis de Piro, at Casal Lia. April 26, 1860., 1860 April 26; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 23.5 x 18 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      The Marquis de Piro was member of an aristocratic Maltese family whose history is bound up with the Knights of St. John. Casal Lia is a small village roughly in the center of the island of Malta.
      B1977.14.22191
      Watercolors; Towers; Casal Lia (Malta); Piro, Adriano, Marquis de, 1817-1866
    - 82. Malta. The tomb of Hannibal, on Ras Benhisa. May 17, 1860., 1860 May 17; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 17 x 25 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      B1977.14.22192
      Tombs; Benghiza (Malta); Watercolors; Hannibal, 247 B.C.-182 B.C.
    - 83. Malta. The church and village of Milleha. May 19, 1860., 1860 May 19; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 18 x 25.5 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      A traveler in 1838 described the town of Millieha as about "an hour's ride form St. Paul's Bay". The Church of Millieha, much visited by devout Maltese, was partly cut out of solid rock. Several objects dedicated to the Virgin, to whom the church is dedicated, were housed inside (Badger 286).
      B1977.14.22193
      Church Buildings; Mellieha (Malta); Watercolors
    - 84. Malta. Calypso's Grotto, near Casal Milleha. May 19, 1860., 1860 May 19; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 18 x 25.5 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      A set of caves described as "Calyspo's Grotto" were so called because they were thought to be described by Homer: "large was the grot in which the nymph be found" (fifth book) (Badger 288). In 1838, a British traveler writes: "Any admirer of natural scenery will be delighted with the prospect which stretches before the sight from the summit of this hill. The green spot beneath, washed at its base by the Bay of Mellieha, the islands of Gozo and Comino in the distance, and the rugged heights around, form a coup d'oeil not everywhere to be enjoyed in the island of Malta" (Badger 289).
      B1977.14.22194
      Watercolors; Malta; Caves
    - 85. Malta. Dungeons on the east side of the Dockyard Creek, formerly occupied by the galley slaves. April 13, 1858., 1858 April 13; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 18 x 25.5 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      B1977.14.22160
      Watercolors; Malta; Prisons
    - 86. Gozo. Fort Chambray, and the principal landing place. June 3, 1859., 1859 June 3; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 17.75 x 25.25 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      Constructed in the mid-18th century, Fort Chambray on the island of Gozo (part of the Maltese Archipelago) rises up from the sea and contains a sizeable barracks. It was briefly occupied by British troops during the Crimean War (1853-56).
      B1977.14.22177
      Watercolors; Gozo Island (Malta); Fort Chambray (Mġarr, Gozo, Malta)
    - 87. Gozo. Phoenician ruins of the Giant's Tower. June 3, 1859., 1859 June 3; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 18 x 25.5 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      B1977.14.22178
      The "Giant's Tower" refers to the Ġgantija temple complex, thought to be constructed in Malta around 3500 BCE. These megalithic temples are the oldest stone structures of this magnitude, and thought to be dedicated to a fertility cult, by the presence of several thousand statuettes of the "Venus" type (Sorlini 140).
      Megalithic monuments; Watercolors; Antiquities; Temples -- Malta; Gozo Island (Malta)
    - 88. Gozo. Citadel at Rabbato. June 3, 1859., 1859 June 3; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 17 x 24.75 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      B1977.14.22179
      The capital city on the island of Gozo is Rabbato, which was re-named "Victoria" by the British in the late 19th century. The city is dominated by a citadel, Il Castello, the site of fortifications since ancient Phoenicians ruled the island.
      Fortification; Rabat (Gozo Island, Malta); Gozo Island (Malta); Watercolors
    - 94. H.M. despatch vessel Vigilant, and gun boat Boxer. October 12, 1857., 1857 October 12; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 23.5 x 36 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      This view perhaps records British vessels anchored at Dockyard Creek, Valetta. Porcher would later depart for Benghazi in the HMS Boxer in November 1860.
      B.1977.14.22155
      Watercolors; Valletta (Malta); Boxer (Ship: 1855-1865); Vigilant (Ship: 1857)
    - 96. Sicily. The Castle of Aci, and the Cyclops, at the foot of Mount Aetna. July 25. 1860.", 1860 July 25; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 25 x 35.5 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      Visible within Porcher's view is the Aci Castello, a Norman castle built in the eleventh century, and the surrounding town after the castle's namesake. These are at the base of the volcanic Mount Etna, said to be the home of the Cyclops.
      B1977.14.22198
      Watercolors; Aci Castello (Italy); Etna, Mount (Italy)
    - H.M. Despatch boat 'Lapwing' May 14th, 1859., 1859 May 14; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 20 x 28 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      B.1977.14.22176
      Watercolors; Lapwing (Ship: 1856-1864)
    - In the palace at Malta. The trumpet on which was sounded the retreat, on the final departure of the Knights of St. John from Rhodes. December A.D. 1522. Presented as a relic with great care by the Grand Masters. Sketched 29th March 1860., 1860 March 29; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 17 x 24 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      Porcher's image represents an artifact from the Siege of Rhodes (1522), when the Ottomans under Sultan Suleyman I expelled the Order of St. John from the Island of Rhodes (now Greece). Sir Ernest Barker describes the events: "Early in the morning of New Year's Day, 1523, the trumpet of the Knights sounded for the last time in Rhodes; their fleet of thirty-one ships, with the refugees on board, put out to sea." (Baker 51). Fifty vessels and approximately 5000 Rhodians departed the island, which was of strategic importance to the Turks, lying between Constantinople and Alexandria. In 1530, Charles V of Spain gave the Knights of St John control of the Maltese islands, but they became vassals of the King and pledged oath to the King of Sicily (Atauz 82).
      B. 1977.14.22197
      Watercolors; Relics; Rhodes (Greece: Island) -- History -- Siege, 1522; Knights of Malta. Fort St. Angelo (Birgu, Malta)
    - Sword, and dress of Dragut, Rais Pashaw of Tripoli, and Commander in Chief of the Turkish Army, in which he was killed at Fort Tigne in the great siege of Malta. Mortally wounded 18th June. Died 23rd June 1565. The same day on which St. Elmo fell into the hands of the enemy., 1860?; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 17 x 24 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      Turgut Reis (also known as Dragut Rais) was a privateer and head of the Barbary Corsairs who led the victorious campaign against Tripoli in 1551 for Suleyman the Magnificent. He also led the Siege of Malta, the culmination of struggles in the Mediterranean beginning with Ottoman control of Tunisia (Keyvanian 49). In 1565, Suleyman ordered the Siege of Malta. After leading the capture of Fort St. Elmo, Turgut Reis was struck by shot from cannon fire from Fort St. Angelo that fell near the Turkish battery. He was mortally wounded, creating a tremendous set-back for Turkish forces.
      B.1977.14.22188
      Malta -- History -- Siege, 1565; Relics; Watercolors; Turgut Reis, 1485-1565
  - Drawings in North Africa (associated with the Nathan Davis expedition)
    - 69. Tunis. A detached fort and mosque near the town. May 14th 1858., 1858 May 14; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 26 x 36 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      B1977.14.22161
      Watercolors; Tunis (Tunisia); Fortification
    - 70. Tunis. The ruins of Baal Hammon Molech, or Saturn, at Carthage, with the mountain of Hamman El-enf in the distance. February 10th, 1860. Published in Davis's 'Carthage and Her Remains.', 1860 February 10; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: Watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 25.25 x 35.5 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      This view was published in Nathan Davis's publication, Carthage and Her Remains. Davis writes that the remains of the Molech structure was being used as materials for modern buildings (he includes a ground plan on page 148 of his publication). Described as vaulted structure, most likely surmounted by a triple dome, Davis concludes it must have contained a series of galleries and circular pilasters: "twelve to represent the twelve months, and four times twelve the forty-eight weeks of the ancient year." Its circular form symbolic of the earth's orbit, Davis is certain that it is a temple of Saturn, "the Baal Hammon of the Carthaginians, or Cronus… the God of Time" (Davis 231). Davis imagines that the temple once contained a terrifying image of Baal. A plan of the Dais, interpreted as the Temple of Saturn in the Carthage, is included facing page 177. The date of the watercolor (post-dating the Davis expedition, 1856-59) suggests Porcher was commissioned to return to the site to produce the watercolor for the publication.
      B1977.14.221183
      Excavations (Archaeology); Carthage (Extinct city); Watercolors; Antiquities
    - 71. The mosque of Dowar-Eshutt, on the site of Carthage, with the Church of St. Louis in the background. February 10th, 1860. Published., 1860 February 10; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 25.25 x 35.5 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      After arriving at Carthage, Nathan Davis complains of the conditions of the two existing villages, Moalkah and Dowar-Eshutt: "irregular mass of hovels chiefly built of ancient materials". He begins digging at Carthage, and takes up residence at Dowar-Eshutt. The drawing was published in Davis's account as "Village of Dowar-Eshutt (Scene of the First Excavation)" (page 59).
      Carthage (Extinct city); Mosques; Watercolors
    - 72. General view of Goletta, the sea port of Tunis. May 18th, 1858., 1858 May 18; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 25.5 x 18 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      B1977.14.22162
      Mounted on same card with "73. The Taenia or neck of land looking towards Utica, taken from the sand hills of Camart. February 9th, 1860."
      Tunis (Tunisia); La Goulette (Tunisia); Watercolors
    - 73. The Taenia or neck of land looking towards Utica, taken from the sand hills of Camart. February 9th, 1860., 1860 February 9; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 25.5 x 18 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      Mounted on same card with "72. General View of Goletta, the Sea Port of Tunis. May 18th, 1858."
      B1977.14.22163
      Utica (Extinct city); Tunis (Tunisia); Camart (Tunisia); Watercolors
    - 74. Carthage. Dr Davis's house at Camart. May 19th 1858., 1858 May 19; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 25.5 x 18 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      Porcher's depiction of Nathan Davis's residence while at Camart, as seen through an archway, opposite. The Harpy arrived at La Goulette on May 14, and sailed the same day for Utica (see logbook).
      Mounted on same card with "75. Village of Camart. The Western extreme of Carthage, with the round Palace of Ben-Ayed. Feb. 9th, 1860. Published."
      B1977.14.22164
      Watercolors; Tunis (Tunisia); Camart (Tunisia); Davis, N. (Nathan), 1812-1882
    - 75. Village of Camart. The western extreme of Carthage, with the round palace of Ben-Ayed. Feb. 9th, 1860. Published., 1860 February 9; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 25.25 x 18 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      This image was engraved for Nathan Davis's Carthage and Her Remains (page 387). Whereas Porcher's watercolor is in a very loose style, and includes three figures, the engraving adds two additional figures conversing. It also renders the palace on the hill more visible. Davis describes the "Jebel Khawi," the Catacomb Hills at Camart as a vast network of catacombs. "To the right in our sketch" the excavations unearthed the ruins of a Roman mausoleum, and remove some pavement and a broken statue. The date of Porcher's watercolors suggests that he returned to the site to produce additional watercolors for Davis's publication (post-dates Davis expedition).
      Mounted on same card with "74. Carthage. Dr Davis's house at Camart. May 19th 1858."
      B1977.14.22165
      Watercolors; Camart (Tunisia); Carthage (Extinct city); Antiquities
    - 76. Light house on the Cani Rocks, at the entrance of the Gulf of Tunis. June 29, 1860, 1860 June 29; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 25.25 x 16 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      Mounted on the same card with "77. The Tombs of Dr. Fallon and J. Triggs (Seaman) who were drowned near the town of Farina, in the Gulf of Tunis."
      B1977.14.22169
      Watercolors; Tunis, Gulf of (Tunisia); Lighthouses; Cani Rocks (Tunisia)
    - 77. The tombs of Dr. Fallon and J. Trigg (Seaman) who were drowned near the town of Farina, in the Gulf of Tunis. May 29, 1858., 1858 May 29; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 25.25 x 16 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      Mounted on the same card with "76. Light house on the Cani Rocks, at the entrance of the Gulf of Tunis. June 29, 1860."
      B1977.14.22170
      Tunis, Gulf of (Tunisia); Ghar al Milh (Tunisia); Watercolors; Tombs
    - 78. Tunis. Porto Farina, taken from the bottom of the bay on the road to Oaga and Utica. June 14th, 1858., 1858 June 14; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 26 x 36 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)
      Nathan Davis describes Porto Farina as "an unwalled town…situated at the foot of a row of hills, and near a large lake, at the extremity of which there is a very handsome large basin for holding the men-of-war and cruisers belonging to Tunis, it being the safest and best port belonging to the kingdom" (Davis 403).
      B1977.14.22173
      Watercolors; Ghar al Milh (Tunisia); Tunis, Gulf of (Tunisia)
    - 79. General view of the site of Utica. June 10th, 1858. Published., 1858 June 10; Porcher, Edwin Augustus, 1824-1878; 1 drawing: watercolor, body color, on medium-thick beige paper, affixed to card mount; sheet 26 x 36 cm, mount 36.5 x 52 cm (Box Oversize 2)